＜地愚蔵:
謎の怪人 地愚蔵に捕らえられ➡
Hijikata and Okita have been captured by the mysterious man, Jigzaw,
and locked up in a deserted building.
廃屋の一室に
閉じ込められてしまった➡
土方と沖田｡
彼らが脱出するには
地愚蔵から与えられた➡
In order to escape, they must obtain a single key provided by Jigzaw.
１つの鍵を手に入れるしかない｡
しかし その鍵を使い鎖を解き➡
But only one person can use the key to unlock his chains and escape the room.
部屋から脱出できるのは
どちらか１人だった｡
When one's shackle is released, the other's will explode.
一方が枷を外せば
もう一方の枷は爆発する｡
And if one of them doesn't escape soon,
しかも
どちらかが早く脱出しなければ➡
the Shinsengumi station will be blown to pieces by Jigzaw's bomb.
真選組屯所は
地愚蔵の仕掛けた爆弾で➡
消し飛んでしまう｡
Kill one comrade to save the others.
仲間を救うために仲間を殺す｡
That would be the game of death Jigzaw has given the Shinsengumi to test their strong bond.
そう それは地愚蔵が 強い絆で
結ばれた真選組に仕掛けた➡
死のｹﾞｰﾑにほかならなかった｡
そして地愚蔵の放った➡
And as for the new assassin Jigzaw has unleashed...?
新たなる刺客とは？
What will happen to the Shinsengumi?
真選組は いったい
どうなってしまうのであろうか＞
Why are you doing the summary?!
(土方)なんで
お前があらすじ語ってんだよ！
What will happen, my ass!
果たして どうなってしまうのか
じゃねえだろ！
お前が しでかしたことだろ｡
You're the one who set this whole thing up!
Why are you talking like you have nothing to do with this?!
なに ひと事みたいに語ってんだ｡
The hell is wrong with your head?!
お前の頭のほうが
どうなってんだ!?
前回見逃した視聴者への配慮だ｡
I'm being considerate for the audience who missed the previous episode.
わかりづらいと困るだろ｡
We want to help them understand what's going on.
How come you're nice to the audience?!
なんで 視聴者には優しいんだよ！
Th-That's...
(沖田)ありゃあ…｡
な なんだ？
Wh-What...
I would like to introduce...
(地愚蔵)紹介しよう｡
私の愛犬でね 喜久蔵だ｡
...my beloved dog, Kickzaw.
[Note: Kickzaw is a play on Kikuzo, the name of popular comic storyteller, Kikuzo Hayashiya]
なかなか かわいいだろ？
Isn't he adorable?
He has an odd habit.
彼は妙なｸｾがあってねぇ｡
He always tends to pick up shiny objects when we go for a walk.
いつも散歩に行くと どこからか
光物ばかり拾ってくる｡
Well, let's see what he picked up today.
さて 今日はいったい
何を拾ってくるのか楽しみだ｡
ﾊﾊﾊ… ﾜﾊﾊﾊ…｡
《土方:ｱﾜﾜ… 危ねえ～！
N-N-N-N-Not good!
やばい これはやばい｡
This is bad!
Very bad!
このままじゃ
確実に持ってかれる！
He's definitely going to take it!
四の五の言ってる場合じゃねえ｡
This isn't the time to whine about details!
Getting backstabbed is no longer the problem!
裏切りとか言ってるﾚﾍﾞﾙじゃねえ｡
あれ 持ってかれたらおしまいだ｡
If he takes it, it's over!
脱出も屯所爆破阻止も
すべておしまいだ！》
No more escape or preventing the station from blowing up!
Huh? Hijikata-san, you're sweating really hard.
あれ 土方さん 汗ひどいですよ｡
ひょっとして鍵 取られるの
怖がってんですか？
Are you scared about the key being taken?
Huh? What?
え？ 何？ 全然｡ 全然だけど｡
No way. Not at all.
What are you talking about?
何言ってんの？
いらねえって言ったじゃん｡
I said we didn't need it.
全然必要ないじゃん あんなの｡
It's totally unnecessary.
That's right.
そうですよね｡
あんな裏切りの道具➡
We don't need that traitor's tool.
必要ないですよね？
必要ねえよ｡
Don't need it.
ｵﾚたち
自分の力で何とかするしよ｡
We'll break out of here with our own power.
Hijikata!
《土方～！ 一歩でも動いてみろ｡
Move one step.
裏切り者として
即刻 粛清してやる》
I'll instantly purge you as a traitor!
《総悟！
ﾃﾒｴ 状況わかってんのかぁ!?》
Sogo!
Do you understand the situation we're in?!
Hurry up!
《沖田:早く～
早く裏切れ 土方～！
Hurry up and betray me, Hijikata!
お願い 300円あげるから》
Please, I'll give you 300 yen.
Go, Sogo!
《土方:いけ～ 総悟！
Don't be so stubborn!
意地張ってんじゃねえぞ 頼む
裏切ってくれぇ！》
Please betray me already!
K-Kickzaw!
き 喜久蔵！ 待て おすわり！
Wait!
Sit! Stay!
ﾁﾝﾁﾝ！ お手！ ﾁﾝﾁﾝ ﾁﾝﾁﾝ!!
Shake hands! Stay!
Stay! Stay!
Can't you hear what I'm saying?!
って言っただろ この野郎
殺されてえのか ｸｿ犬～！
Want me to kill you, stupid dog?!
(土方)止まった｡
He stopped.
ふぅ よかっ…｡
What a relief...
き 喜久蔵～！
K-Kickzaw!
ふぅ 無事…｡
Safe...
《しまった！》
D-Damn it!
Hijikata!
土方～！ ついにｼｯﾎﾟを出したな｡
You've finally showed your true colors!
裏切り者として
一番隊隊長 沖田総悟が➡
Sogo Okita, Captain of the 1st Division, shall purge you as a traitor!
粛清仕る！
I-It'd be dangerous if the dog swallowed it.
い 犬が飲み込むと危ないからな｡
よし これで大丈夫だ｡
Okay, now it's safe.
Wh-What are you doing?!
(沖田)な 何しとんじゃあ～！
["When breaking a Chuubert in half, the end with the knob should be better. It's also tasty to drink from there."]
(鎖を打つ音)
み 水を… 誰か水を…｡
W-Water...
Somebody give me water...
ﾀﾞ ﾀﾞﾒだ…
もう 体がいうことをきかん｡
I-It's useless...
My body won't listen to me...
土方さん もう限界です｡
Hijikata-san, this is it.
We've spent two days beating on this pipe without any sleep.
ｵﾚたち 丸２日一睡もせずに
ﾊﾟｲﾌﾟ叩き続けているんですよ｡
ﾒｼにいたっては もう３日｡
It's been three days since we've had anything to eat...
Yet we haven't even found a single clue to aid our escape.
なのに 一向に
脱出の糸口は見つからない｡
(土方)
立て 総悟 ｵﾚたちの肩には➡
Stand up, Sogo...
The fate of the Shinsengumi rests on our shoulders...
真選組の命運がかかってんだ｡
Less than 24 hours left before the station will be blown up...
屯所爆破まで
ついに 24時間をきっちまった｡
急がなければ 早くここから
脱出しなければ…｡
We have to hurry...
Hurry up and escape...
ごきげんよう 土方君 沖田君｡
Good day, Hijikata-kun, Okita-kun.
Hey!
(土方)
おい！ 仮面半分 脱げかけてんぞ｡
Your mask is half off.
You have less than a day left
屯所爆破まで あのｱﾚ➡
１日 きっちゃったね｡
till the station explodes.
He's eating a Chuubert!
[Note: Spoof of Japanese ice candy, Tupet.]
(土方)ﾁｭｰﾊﾟｯﾄ食ってるよ
段々 ﾐｽﾃﾘｱｽｷｬﾗ演じるの➡
It's like he's tired of pretending to be a mysterious character!
面倒くさくなってるよ ｱｲﾂ｡
Oh?
(地愚蔵)おやおや？ 屯所の前に
ｷﾐたちのほうが先に➡
It appears that you two will collapse before the station does.
力 尽きてしまいそうな
勢いじゃないか ｸｸｸ…｡
Are you hungry?
お腹が空いたかい？
Do you want some water?
水が飲みたいかい？
I'm pissed! He's pissing me off!
腹立つ！ ｱｲﾂ 腹立つ!!
(地愚蔵)ﾊﾞｶな人たちだ｡
Fools.
I gave you a chance to escape and save the station,
せっかく ここから脱出して
屯所を救うﾁｬﾝｽを➡
くれてやったというのに
まさか それを➡
yet you threw it away...
自ら捨ててしまうとは｡
However, I have seen many people spout noble ideology under a thin mask,
しかし これまで
薄っぺらい仮面をつけ➡
きれい事ばかり並べるﾔﾂは
たくさん見てきたが➡
ここまで分厚い仮面を
つけている連中を見たのは➡
but you are the first ones with such a thick mask.
ｷﾐたちが はじめてだよ｡
However, in the end, you still won't have been able to escape.
しかし 結果として
未だにｷﾐたちは➡
ここから脱してはいない
ｷﾐたちの選んだ選択肢は➡
It may appear that you are acting in the best interests of your comrades,
仲間を思いやったように見えて➡
所詮 自らの手を汚すことを嫌い➡
but in reality, you merely don't want to dirty your hands and will cause many of them to die.
多くの仲間を
見殺しにしたことに他ならない｡
このまま全員 仲よく滅んでいく
姿を眺めるのもいいが➡
I wouldn't mind seeing you all perish together,
but that wouldn't make for a fun game.
それじゃあ ｹﾞｰﾑとして退屈だ｡
最後に もう一度だけ
ｷﾐたちにﾁｬﾝｽをやる｡
I shall give you one last chance.
Okay?
いいか これを逃せば➡
If you lose this chance, there won't be any way to save you or the Shinsengumi.
もうｷﾐたちも
真選組も助かる道はない｡
ｷﾐたちの両ｻｲﾄﾞにあるﾛｯｶｰ｡
There are lockers on each side of you.
Check the locker furthest in.
その いちばん奥の
ﾛｯｶｰを調べてみるんだ｡
そこに ここを
脱出するための もう１つの➡
I've placed another key item there for helping you escape.
ｷｰｱｲﾃﾑを用意してある｡
Now go.
さぁ 行くがいい｡
The time has come to shed those fake masks.
偽りの仮面を
取り去るときは来た｡
Show me your true selves!
ｷﾐたちの素顔を私に見せてみろ｡
The ugliness hidden behind those masks!
仮面に隠された その醜い姿を…｡
ｸｸｸ…｡
(母)ﾋﾛ君 ﾌｧﾐ通 買ってきたわよ｡
[Note: Famitsu is a popular video game magazine in Japan.]
Hiro-kun, I bought your Famitsu!
Hey, your mom's back again, Hiro-kun.
(土方)おい また
おかあさん来てんぞ ﾋﾛ君｡
What? My mom? What are you talking about?
お母さん？ 何を言っている｡
I am Jigzaw, born from nothingness.
私は虚無から生まれし者
地愚蔵だぞ｡
I have no mother.
お母さんなど 私には存在しない｡
Hiro-kun, why is your door locked?
(母)ﾋﾛ君 どうして部屋に
鍵かけてるの！
Hey, be quiet!
ちょ うるさい！ 隣の部屋の人が
うるさいなぁ もう｡
The neighbors are so loud.
No, you don't need to bother hiding it.
(土方)いや もう隠さんでいいから
おかあさんだろう？
It's your mom, right?
顔 見たし挨拶させろよ｡
We already saw her face so let us say hi.
I said she's not my mom!
お母さんじゃねえって
言ってんだろ！
Don't mess with me, damn it!
いい加減にしろよ ｺﾗ！
(父)お母さん｡
Honey, move out of the way!
ちょっと どいてなさい！
ﾋﾛｼ!! お父さん 話があるんだ｡
Hiroshi!
I need to talk to you.
お前 今日も学校 休んだらしいな｡
It seems that you were absent from school again today.
(土方)おとうさん!?
今度 おとうさん出てきたよ｡
Your dad?!
Now your dad showed up!
Stupid hag!
ｸｿﾊﾞﾊﾞｱ！ ﾁｸってんじゃねえよ!!
つうか 出てくるな!!
Don't go spilling everything! And don't...
おい！ ｱｲﾂもう
ﾐｽﾃﾘｱｽでも何でもねえよ!!
Hey!
There's nothing mysterious about that guy!
ﾌｧﾐ通 読んでたよ
かあちゃんにだけ強気だったよ｡
He reads Famitsu!
He only acts strong when he's talking to his mom!
ｱｲﾂが いちばん
仮面 脱げかけてんじゃねえか！
He's the one who's letting his mask fall off!
ったく ただの
引きこもりのｶﾞｷじゃねえか｡
Man, he's just some withdrawn brat...
土方さん ｺｲﾂを見てください｡
Hijikata-san, look at this.
冷蔵庫？
A fridge...?
何かの罠か？
開けてみましょう｡
Is this some kind of trap?
Let's open it up.
ちょっと待て！
ﾔﾂのことだ!! 何か企んでるに…｡
Hey, wait!
That guy's gotta be plotting something...
In that case, do you intend to just stand around doing nothing?
だったら このまま何もせずに➡
つっ立ってるつもりですかい？
I'm opening it.
開けやすぜ｡
これは！
何だ!?
This is...!
What?
(沖田)ﾁｭｰﾊﾟｯﾄです ｸﾞﾚｰﾌﾟ味｡
A Chuubert. Grape-flavored.
(土方)何の役に立つんだよ!?
How is that supposed to help?!
ｹﾞｰﾑが終わる前に 餓死されちゃ
困ると思ったんですかね…｡
He probably didn't want us to starve to death before the game ended.
Then give us something more substantial!
だったら 他のもん用意しろよ！
じゃあ ｵﾚ
下の長いほうで いいですか？
So, can I have the longer lower part?
下？ 下が長い？
ｵﾒｴ なに言ってんだ？
Lower?
Lower is longer?
What are you talking about?
下っていったら そっちでさあ｡
Lower, as in you know, the side you hold.
その 持つところあるほう｡
いや これ 持つところじゃなくて
飲むところだから｡
No, that's where you drink from not where you hold it.
はぁ？ 飲むところなら ほら…
そこに あるじゃないですか｡
You drink it from here.
Just break here...
そこを 折って…｡
あ～ん!?
Hah? You snip off this part and suck on it! That's what makes it a Chuubert!
ここ切って ﾁｭｰﾁｭｰ吸うから
ﾁｭｰﾊﾟｯﾄつうんだろ？
ﾁｭｰﾁｭｰ吸って 最後に甘くない氷が
残ったりするから➡
It's a Chuubert cause you suck on it till there's only flavorless ice left.
ﾁｭｰﾊﾟｯﾄなんだろうが！
だいたい
こんな所で折っちまったら➡
Besides, if you eat it by breaking here, the other side will melt!
片方 食ってる間に
もう片方 溶けちまうだろうが！
基本 ﾁｭｰﾊﾟｯﾄは そこを折って
分け合うもんでしょう？
Chuuberts are usually broken in half and split.
ｵﾚは いつも 姉上と➡
I used to have big arguments with my sister about who would get which half.
どっちを食べるかで
喧々諤々 やってましたけどね｡
いちいち 真ん中で折るって➡
Break it in half every time?
お前 全国の一人っ子たちは
どうすりゃ いいんだよ？
Then what are all the only children in the country supposed to do?
They can just get their hands all sticky.
手 ﾍﾞﾀﾍﾞﾀになりゃあ
いいじゃないですかね｡
あ～ お前 今 全国の一人っ子たち
敵に回したぞ！
Yeah, you just provoked every single only child in the country!
絶対 回したね うん！
いいですぜ｡
You definitely did, yeah.
That's fine.
世界じゅう 敵に回したって
これだけは 譲れねえ｡
I won't budge on this, even if it means making enemies around the world.
そこは断じて 持つところでさあ｡
That is where you're supposed to hold it.
凍らせるだけが 食べ方じゃねえ｡
People don't always freeze them before they eat them, you know.
冷やして
液体で飲む場合のことも考えろ｡
You have to consider when people just drink them as a cold liquid.
こんなとこ へし折ったら
その瞬間 大惨事だろうが！
If you break here, that'll make a huge mess.
熱でも あるんですかい？
Do you have a fever or something?
ﾁｭｰﾊﾟｯﾄは もともと
凍らせるもんでしょうが｡
Chuuberts are supposed to be frozen.
目え覚ませ 総悟！
この突起は 切るためにある！
Wake up, Sogo.
This protruding edge is supposed to be cut.
あれは 誰が何と言おうと
持つところでさあ｡
I don't care what anyone says. That's where you hold it.
じゃなきゃ
あんな 乳首みてえなもん…｡
Or it wouldn't look like a nipple.
Hey, what did you just say?
おい お前 今 何て言った？
はっ？
Huh?
乳首… ですかい？
Nipple? You mean?
乳首は 何のためにある？
What are nipples meant for?
あっ…｡
Ah.
はい！ じゃあ そんなわけで
今日のｻﾌﾞﾀｲﾄﾙ 修正な！
Yes, that's right! So we have to change the title for this episode!
["When breaking a Chuubert in half, the end with the knob should be better. Normally, the knob part is used to drink the Chuubert."]
That's right!
そうだよ！
乳首は 吸うために あるんだよ！
Nipples are supposed to be sucked! Got it?
わかったか！
じゃあ ｵﾚ➡
Then can I have the longer upper part?
上の長いほうで いいですか？
The part with the nipple?
乳首ありのほう
もらっていいですか？
ｼﾞｬﾝｹﾝで 決めようか？
Let's use rock-paper-scissors to decide.
そういや もう一個
ｱｲﾃﾑが あるって言ってたな｡
Say... He mentioned something about another item.
こっちは 糸のこぎりだ｡
We've got a coping saw here.
ｺｲﾂで 鎖を切れってのか｡
Are we supposed to cut through the chain with this?
簡単には この鎖は切れねえって
言ってたのは ｱｲﾂですがね｡
He was the one who said the chain wouldn't be easily cut through.
ぬっ… くっ… 切れねえな これ｡
Can't cut through this...
ふぬぬぬ…｡
ぬぬぬぬ…｡
ﾊｧ ﾊｧ… やっぱ ﾀﾞﾒだ…｡
It's no use.
まるで 歯が立たねえ…｡
A futile effort.
Besides, considering how much stamina we have left...
第一 今の体力じゃ…｡
鎖はﾀﾞﾒ｡ ﾊﾟｲﾌﾟもﾀﾞﾒ｡
The chain's no good, the pipe's no good...
あとは 切れるところといえば…｡
The only other thing to cut is...
総悟!? しっかりしろ おい！
Sogo?!
Get a grip! Hey!
土方さん すいやせん…｡
I'm sorry, Hijikata-san.
どうにも ｵﾚは 限界みてえです｡
Looks like I can't go on anymore.
Get a hold of yourself!
しっかりしろ！
今 ﾁｭｰﾊﾟｯﾄ 飲ましてやる！
I'll give you a drink of this Chuubert!
ほら しっかりしろ！ いい感じに
ﾁｭｰﾊﾟｯﾄも溶けてきてる！
Come on! Get a grip!
It's pretty much melted already.
どうした 総悟！
なに やってんだ 早く飲め！
What's wrong, Sogo?! Hurry up and drink!
ﾊ… ﾊﾊｯ… 飲めませんよ…｡
I can't drink it.
でかいのは
土方さんが 飲みてえんでしょう？
You want to drink the big side, don't you?
お前…｡
You...
ﾌｯ… 土方さん…
ｱﾝﾀ 結局 そういうﾔﾂさ｡
Hijikata-san, that's how you always are...
ｵﾚに張り合って 悪ぶって
殺し合いなんて演じたところで➡
You compete with me and act tough like you want to kill me,
結局 根っこまでは
悪に なりきれてねえ｡
but deep down inside, you aren't bad enough.
いざ 相手が死にかければ➡
When you see your opponent on the verge of death,
迷わず
長いほうのﾁｭｰﾊﾟｯﾄを差し出す｡
you don't hesitate to offer the longer side of the Chuubert.
ｵﾚが ｱﾝﾀなら 短いほうどころか
全部 １人で飲み干します｡
If I were in your shoes,
I'd drink both sides myself.
それくらい しなきゃ
ｵﾚには 勝てやせんぜ 土方さん｡
If you aren't capable of that, you'll never beat me, Hijikata-san.
土方さん… ｵﾚは 昔から➡
Hijikata-san...
I always couldn't stand that side of you.
ｱﾝﾀの そういうところが
気に食わなかった｡
ｵﾚの 理解できないことをするﾔﾂ｡
The guy who did things I couldn't understand.
ｵﾚの思いどおりに ならないﾔﾂ｡
The guy who wouldn't do what I wanted.
今まで 嫌がらせばかりして➡
I've pestered you this whole time to drag you down.
さんざん 足 引っ張ってきたが➡
でも 今にして思えば ｵﾚは➡
But looking back now, I don't think I actually hated you.
ｱﾝﾀのことが嫌いだったわけじゃ
ない気がする｡
ｵﾚは ただ…➡
I was probably just jealous...
ｱﾝﾀが うらやましかった
だけなのかもしれない｡
ｵﾚのできないことを
容易にやってのけるﾔﾂを…➡
...jealous of the guy who could easily do the things I couldn't.
ｵﾚの持っていないものを
持っているﾔﾂを…｡
...of the guy who possessed what I didn't.
土方さん… 今まで…➡
Hijikata-san...
Sorry about causing you so much trouble...
いろいろ迷惑かけて
すいませんでした｡
な… 何言ってんだ 総悟｡
Wh-What are you saying, Sogo?
お前が… お前が ｵﾚに
そんなこと言うたまかよ｡
When... When did you start talking like that to me?
らしくねえじゃねえか｡
ｶﾞﾗじゃねえじゃねえか！
This isn't like you.
You're not cut out for this stuff.
ﾍ… ﾍﾍ…
自分でも そう思いまさぁ｡
I feel the same way.
だけど 今言わなきゃ…➡
But I have to tell you now...
一生
言いそびれちまいそうなんでね｡
It feels like I won't get another chance.
ばっ ﾊﾞｶ野郎！
S-Stupid!
Don't get all weak on me!
弱気になってんじゃねえよ！
多少 ﾒｼ抜いたくらいで➡
Don't act so pathetic just because you've missed a few meals!
何 情けねえこと言ってんだ!!
しっかりしやがれ！
お前が こんなことで死ぬかよ！
Get a grip!
You're not going to die from this!
腹が減ったんなら いくらでも
ﾁｭｰﾊﾟｯﾄくらい飲ませてやる！
If you're hungry, I'll let you drink as much of this Chuubert as you want!
ほら ｵﾚの分も飲みやがれ！
Come on!
Have my share, too!
土方さん… わかんねえんですか？
Hijikata-san.
Don't you understand?
ｵﾚは 最後くらい
ｱﾝﾀのｼﾞｬﾏは したくねえんですよ｡
At least for this one last time, I don't want to get in your way...
ｵﾚには もう… これは必要ねえ｡
I don't need this anymore.
ｵﾚに必要なのは あっちのほうだ｡
What I need is over there.
ｱﾝﾀも
ほんとは 気づいてんでしょう？
You've probably realized what the coping saw is for.
あの 糸のこぎりの使い方｡
これは 鎖を切るためでも
ﾊﾟｲﾌﾟを切るためのもんでもねえ｡
It's not for cutting the chain or the pipe.
ｵﾚたちのうちの どちらかの
首を落とすためのもんだ｡
It's to cut off one of our heads.
枷を外さなくても これで
どちらかの首を切断すれば➡
Even if we can't remove the shackles,
if we cut off one person's head, we can slide the chain off the pipe.
あのﾊﾟｲﾌﾟから
鎖を外すことができる｡
野郎は あくまで…➡
He's intent on making us kill one another.
ｵﾚたちに 殺し合いを
演じさせるつもりなんだ｡
黙れ｡ いいから ﾁｭｰﾊﾟｯﾄを飲め｡
Shut up.
Just drink the Chuubert.
土方さん… 本来なら真っ先に➡
Hijikata-san...
Under normal circumstances, I would have jumped and beheaded you right off the bat.
ｱﾝﾀに飛びかかって
首かっきるところだ｡
だが あいにく…
ｵﾚに そんな力は もう残ってねえ｡
But unfortunately, I don't have enough strength left to do that...
それができたとしても➡
Even if I did, I still wouldn't be able to make it to the station...
屯所まで行くなんて
まず不可能だ｡
黙れつってんだ｡ 早く飲め｡
I told you to shut up.
Hurry up and drink this.
土方さん… もう時間はねえ｡
Hijikata-san, we're out of time.
こっから出る方法も
もう それしかねえ｡
It's the only way out of this place.
黙れ…｡
Shut up...
土方さん… 悔しいけど➡
Hijikata-san...
It hurts me to say this, but you're the only one left who can save the Shinsengumi.
真選組 救えんのは
もうｱﾝﾀしか 残って…｡
Didn't you hear me tell you to shut up?!
黙れってのが聞こえねえのかよ!!
副長命令だ｡
This is an order from the Vice-Chief.
そんなﾏﾈは
このｵﾚが 絶対に許さん｡
I won't let that happen.
あんな
くだらんﾔﾂのために死ぬなんざ➡
I won't let you die for that stupid bastard.
絶対に ｵﾚが許さん！
屯所の連中も… お前も…➡
I won't let you or anyone at the station die!
一人として死ぬことは
ｵﾚが許さん！
ﾃﾒｴは ｵﾚと一緒に
生きて ここから出るんだ!!
You're going to leave this place with me alive!
あきらめんな！
何か方法があるはずだ｡
Don't give up.
There has to be a way.
A way for both of us to escape this place.
２人で脱出できる方法が！
待ってろ｡
まだ 何かあるかもしれねえ！
Hold on.
There might be something else we can use.
ｵﾚが 必ず
脱出の方法を見つけ出してやる！
I'll find a way out of here without fail!
土方さん… 結局 地愚蔵の
言うとおりになっちまいましたね｡
Hijikata-san...
It ended up being like Jigzaw said.
最後の最後で
仮面が外れちまった｡
I had to remove my mask at the very end.
ｱﾝﾀには
いちばん見せたくない素顔…➡
I showed you a side of myself I never wanted you to see.
見せちまったよ ｵﾚは…｡
忘れてくだせえ…
さっき言ったことは 全部｡
Please forget everything I just said.
土方… さん…➡
Hijikata-san...
真選組のこと…➡
Please take care of the Shinsengumi...
よろしく… お願い… します…｡
(拍手)
恐れ入ったよ 土方君 沖田君｡
I am amazed, Hijikata-kun, Okita-kun.
まさか ｷﾐたちの絆というものが
これほどのものとは…｡
I didn't expect your bond to be so strong.
仲間を救うため
仲間同士で殺し合いをという➡
The purpose of the game was
to convince fellow comrades to kill one another for the sake of saving the rest of your comrades,
趣向のｹﾞｰﾑだったんだが
まさか 仲間を救うため➡
but I didn't expect him to choose his own death to save you.
自ら 死を選ぶとは…｡
Your bond is truly strong.
ｷﾐたちの絆こそ 本物だ｡
Or perhaps I should say his bond for you was strong.
いや ｷﾐたちではない｡
彼のと言ったほうがいいのかな｡
内心
ほっとしているんじゃないかね｡
Aren't you relieved inside, Hijikata-kun?
土方君｡ ｸｸｸｸ…｡
これで
自分は助かったと｡
Thinking, "Now I'm saved."
彼は
ｷﾐの命を救っただけではない｡
He didn't only save your life.
自ら 死を選ぶことにより➡
By killing himself, he prevented you from getting your hands dirty.
ｷﾐが 手を汚すことも
阻止したのだ｡
きっと彼は ｷﾐの臆病さを
見抜いていたんだろうね｡
He must have known that you are a coward.
臆病なｷﾐでも
首が落とせるように➡
He died so a coward like you would be able to take his head.
わざわざ 死んでくれたんだ｡
ｷﾐは これを
遂行する義務がある｡
You are obligated to carry through with this.
Now, cut off your friend's head.
さぁ 切り落とすがいい｡
友の首を｡
その欺瞞にあふれた
仮面をつけて➡
Put on the mask of deceit and live for your friend's sake.
友の分も
のうのうと生きていくがいい｡
ｸｸｸｸ… ｱｰﾊｯﾊｯﾊｯﾊ…｡
♪♪～
(地愚蔵)
それは何のﾏﾈだね 土方君｡
What are you doing, Hijikata-kun?
決まってんだろ
首を落としに行くんだ 今すぐに｡
That should be obvious.
I'm heading off to sever a head.
His head is on your shoulder.
(地愚蔵)首なら
のっているじゃないか ｷﾐの肩に｡
(土方)ｵﾚが探してる首は
ｺｲﾂじゃねえ｡
This isn't the head I'm after.
ｵﾚが かっきりたいのは…➡
The one I want to cut off
薄汚ねえ面をかぶった
その首だ!!
is the one wearing that filthy mask!
(地愚蔵)ﾊﾊﾊﾊ…｡
ﾑﾀﾞだよ 土方君｡
It's futile, Hijikata-kun.
自力で そこから
脱せられるわけがあるまい｡
You can't escape from that place on your own.
それは そこにつながれていた
ｷﾐがいちばん知って…｡
You should know that after being chained...
なっ！ ﾊﾞ ﾊﾞｶな！
What?! I-Impossible!
There's a crack in the pipe!
ﾊﾟｲﾌﾟにﾋﾋﾞが入っていく！
まさか 延々と叩き続けていた➡
Are you saying that the pipe couldn't bear the extensive beating which was believed to be futile?!
あのﾑﾀﾞとも
思える作業によって➡
ﾊﾟｲﾌﾟのほうが 耐えきれなくなった
とでもいうのか!!
ﾊﾞｯ ﾊﾞ ﾊﾞｶな!!
I-I-Impossible!
He escaped on his own power!
自力で脱出した!?
《まだ かすかに脈はある｡
He still has a slight pulse.
死なせねえ！
誰一人たりとも死なせやしねえ！
I won't let you die...
I'm not going to let anyone die!
総悟 お前は必ず
ｵﾚが助け…》
Sogo, I'm going to save...
C-Crap!
《し しまった!!》
《こ このままじゃ！
くっ…》
A-At this rate...
《このままじゃ…
鎖のせいで 総悟も道連れだ!!
At this rate, the chain will bring Sogo down, too.
鎖を… 鎖をなんとかしねえと！》
I have to...
I have to do something about the chain!
え…｡
Hijikata-san, good work.
土方さん お疲れっした｡
楽しかったっす｡
It was fun.
また今度
遊んでくだせえ｡
Come play with me again?
《え…｡
え…｡ え…》
あ～あ ﾁｭｰﾊﾟｯﾄのせいで
身体がﾍﾞﾀﾍﾞﾀすらぁ｡ 気持悪い｡
Man, I'm all sticky cause of the Chuubert.
I feel sick.
Ah, the blood was from the Chuubert.
あ ﾁｭｰﾊﾟｯﾄだったんですか
その血｡
あ お疲れ｡
いやぁ いい仕事だったよ｡
Yeah, good work.
You did a great job.
What are you talking about?
なに言ってんすか｡
You put on a convincing act yourself.
沖田さんも
迫真の演技だったじゃないですか｡
なんか ﾓﾉﾛｰｸﾞまで
芝居してましたよね｡
You were even acting when you talked to yourself.
Like you didn't know me at all.
ｵﾚのこと
全然 知らないみたいな｡
あぁ｡ こういうのは
完全になりきらないとﾀﾞﾒだからね｡
Yeah, you have to totally become the part for these things.
Have to deceive even the audience.
視聴者も
騙す感じでいかないと｡
I see.
そうなんですか｡
ｵﾚ 先の展開➡
I thought you just weren't planning ahead.
何も考えてないだけかと
思いましたよ｡ さすがっすわ｡
I'm impressed!
んじゃ 次回
ﾀｰｹﾞｯﾄ決まったら➡
Then, when you decide on the next target, let me know.
また 呼んでくださいね｡
きっとっすよ｡
For sure, okay?
あぁ 次ね｡
Yeah, next time.
I was considering this guy with curly silver hair.
銀髪の天ﾊﾟのﾔﾂに
しようかなって思ってんだけど｡
ｺｲﾂも たぶん
相当 おもしろいよ｡
He should provide plenty of fun.
Well, I can't wait.
楽しみにしてますよ
じゃあ お疲れっした～｡
Good work then!
The next episode...
"If You Can't Beat Them, Join Them."
[The proprietor of Odd Jobs was talking to himself as usual when...]
[...a mysterious man appeared, wielding an incredible power!!]
[See you next time!]